https://www.davestravelpages.com/privacy-policy/

Greece TravelGreek IslandsEuropeAsia TravelAmericasBike TouringAboutLast updated on May 30, 2020 By Dave Briggs Leave a CommentPrivacy Policy for www.davestravelpages.comHi!Thanks for taking the time to read the privacy policy for Dave's Travel Pages. Your privacy is important to me, because I value my own privacy as well! As such, I've kept to a minimum the type of data this website registers, and take all steps to ensure that the data is protected.Let me start by saying what I WON'T sell your data to third parties – That's just weird!This privacy policy was recently updated to be in compliance with the new GDPR regulations in Europe. These have been designed to offer citizens of Europe protection from their personal data being exploited. I'm in total agreement with this, and have taken every step to be in compliance with the regulations. What happens when you visit the siteYour ConsentAdvertsing – After May 25th 2018, visitors to the site from the EU will see a popup asking if they agree to personalised ads served by my advertising partner MediaVine. These ads are likely to be based on your previous browsing experience. You are free to opt in and out as you wish. I collect no data myself from this. Check out the Mediavine specific policy at the end of this post.Why do I have the ads? This website is a business, and a business needs to make money – I'm sure you understand! Newsletter – You may see an option to sign up for various newsletters on the site. You can not be automatically signed up for a newsletter, and I have a double-opt in process so you can't be ‘accidentally' signed up either! It goes without saying that I would need your email details in order to communicate with you. These are stored in my third party service provider who is currently Mailchimp. I only use this for communication with yourself based on the reasons you signed up, and you are free to unsubscribe at any time – there is a link included in each email to do so. Concerned? Don't sign up !Comments – If you decide to leave a comment on the blog, you will be asked for a name and email address. This is so you can be notified of any replies to your comment, and is a key usability feature. Your IP address will also be stored in order to combat spam. I believe this is covered by legitimate interest as the concept of communication, community, and commenting can not function with out this. Concerned? Simply don't leave a comment.CookiesThe website needs to use cookies to function and as part of legitimate business operations. These can be first party cookies as well as third party cookies. These cookies contain no data that I can use to identify you, but are instead designed to help your browsing experience. Internet users have always had full control of the cookies on their computers, and you can access this through your browser settings. I have no way of either tracking the cookies left on your computer or using them to identify you. Analytics – This website uses analytics so that I can further improve my service. I use these to see which pages are the most visited, how I can improve content, and whether my visitors come from search or social media. I have set the ‘Anonymity' feature for the analytics. This means that the last few digits of the IP address are masked from both myself and Google. No one can identify you!Links to external websites – Dave's Travel Pages links to external websites where I think they will provide extra value for you, or as an affiliate as part of my legitimate business. Each site you visit should have its own privacy statement, which I encourage you to read! I have no control over the data they monitor when you visit them. From my end, I will see that someone has clicked through, but I have no way of personally identifying who it was – As it should be! Put SimplyThe short version, is that there are only two occasions in which your personal data is stored by myself – either when you sign up for a newsletter or when you leave a comment. In both circumstances, you have to take proactive steps in which to do so willingly. If I use this data at all, it is only for the purpose it was designed for. I regularly look over data I may have, and erase those things that are no longer needed in full compliance with GDPR.Accessing your informationIf you are still concerned, and would like to access any information you believe I may have or request it be deleted, please contact me directly at – dave@davestravelpages.com. We'll have a chat and sort it out!Mediavine Programmatic AdvertisingThe Website uses Mediavine to manage all third-party advertising on the Website. Mediavine serves content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use first and third-party cookies. A cookie is a small text file which is sent to your computer or mobile device (referred to in this policy as a “device”) by the web server so that a website can remember some information about your browsing activity on the Website. The cookie may collect information relating to your use of the Website, information about your device such as the device’s IP address and browser type, demographic data and, if you arrived at the Website via a link from a third-party site, the URL of the linking page.First party cookies are created by the website that you are visiting. A third-party cookie is frequently used in behavioral advertising and analytics and is created by a domain other than the website you are visiting. Third-party cookies, tags, pixels, beacons and other similar technologies (collectively, “Tags”) may be placed on the Website to monitor interaction with advertising content and to target and optimize advertising. Each internet browser has functionality so that you can block both first and third-party cookies and clear your browser’s cache. The “help” feature of the menu bar on most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to receive notification of new cookies, how to disable existing cookies and how to clear your browser’s cache. For more information about cookies and how to disable them, you can consult the information at www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/.Without cookies you may not be able to take full advantage of the Website content and features. Please note that rejecting cookies does not mean that you will no longer see ads when you visit our Site.The Website may collect IP addresses and location information to serve personalized ads and pass it to Mediavine. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices to opt-in or opt-out of this data collection, please visit http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp. You may also visit http://optout.aboutads.info/#/ and http://optout.networkadvertising.org/# to learn more information about interest-based advertising. You may download the AppChoices app at http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices to opt out in connection with mobile apps, or use the platform controls on your mobile device to opt out.Mediavine partners with the following data processors:Pubmatic. You may find Pubmatic’s privacy policy through this link. The data collected on the Website may be transferred to Pubmatic and its demand partners for interest-based advertising. Statistical information and other non-cookie technologies (such as eTags and web or browser cache) may be used by third parties on this Website. Browser settings that block cookies may have no effect on these technologies, but you may clear your cache to delete such trackers. Data collected from a particular browser or device may be used with another computer or device that is linked to the browser or device on which such data was collected.Criteo. You may find Criteo’s privacy policy through this link. The data collected on the Website may be transferred to Criteo and its demand partners for interest-based advertising. Criteo may collect, access, and use non-identifying data to improve the Criteo Technology and other Criteo products, programs, and/or services. This non-identifying data may include on-site user behavior and user/page content data, URLs, statistics, or internal search queries. The non-identifying data are collected through the ad call and stored with a Criteo cookie for a maximum period of 13 months.Pulsepoint. You may find Pulsepoint’s privacy policy through this link.LiveRamp. You may find LiveRamp’s privacy policy through this link. When you use the Website, we share information that we may collect from you, such as your email (in hashed, de-identified form), IP address or information about your browser or operating system, with LiveRamp Inc, and its group companies (‘LiveRamp’). LiveRamp may use a cookie on your browser and match your shared information to their on- and offline marketing databases and those of its advertising partners to create a link between your browser and information in those other databases. This link may be shared by our partners globally for the purpose of enabling interest-based content or advertising throughout your online experience (e.g. cross device, web, email, in-app, etc.) by third parties unaffiliated with our website. These third parties may in turn link further demographic or interest-based information to your browser. To opt out of LiveRamp’s targeted advertising, please go here: https://liveramp.com/opt_out/RhythmOne. You may view RhythmOne’s privacy policy through this link. RhythmOne uses cookies and similar tracking technologies (such as mobile device identifiers and digital fingerprinting) to provide its services. RhythmOne may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please visit the following webpage: http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp.District M. You may find District M’s privacy policy through this link.YieldMo. You may find YieldMo’s privacy policy through this link. If you want to opt out of receiving interest based ads from Yieldmo or exercise your right under the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”) to opt-out of the sale of your personal information, you may do so through this link.The Rubicon Project. You may find Rubicon’s privacy policy through this link. If you want to opt out of receiving interest based ads from Rubicon or exercise your right under the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”) to opt-out of the sale of your personal information, you may do so through this link. You may also utilize the Network Advertising Initiative’s opt-out page, the Digital Advertising Alliance’s opt-out page, or the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance’s opt-out page.Amazon Publisher Services. You may find Amazon Publisher Services’ privacy policy through this link.AppNexus. You may find the AppNexus privacy policy through this link.OpenX. You may find OpenX’s privacy policy through this link.Verizon Media formerly known as Oath. You may find Verizon Media’s privacy policy through this link. You may also utilize the Network Advertising Initiative’s opt-out page, the Digital Advertising Alliance’s opt-out page, or the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance’s opt-out page to opt-out of the use of cookies for interest-based advertising.TripleLift. You may find TripleLift’s privacy policy through this link. To opt out of receiving interest-based advertising (including retargeting) from TripleLift’s services through the use of cookies in your current browser and for more information on what it means to opt-out, please go to www.triplelift.com/consumer-opt-out.Index Exchange. You may find Index Exchange’s privacy policy through this link. You may also utilize the Network Advertising Initiative’s opt-out page, the Digital Advertising Alliance’s opt-out page, or the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance’s opt-out page to opt-out of the use of cookies for interest-based advertising.Sovrn. You may find Sovrn’s privacy policy through this link.GumGum. You may find GumGum’s privacy policy through this link. GumGum may (i) use place and use cookies on end users’ browsers or use web beacons to collect information about end users who visit such Publisher Websites and (ii) link such collected end user information to other end user information provided by third parties in order to deliver targeted Advertisements to such end users.Digital Remedy. You may find Digital Remedy’s privacy policy through this link.MediaGrid. You may find MediaGrid’s privacy policy through this link. MediaGrid may collect and store information about end-user interactions with this website through cookies, advertising IDS, pixels and server-to-server connections. MediaGrid was receive the following information: the page an End-User has requested and the referring/exit pages; Timestamp information (i.e., the date and time the End-User has visited the page); IP address; mobile device identifier; device model; device operating system; browser type; carrier; gender; age; geolocation (including GPS coordinates); clickstream data; cookie information; first-party identifiers'; and hashed email addresses; demographic and inferred interest information; and post-conversion data (from both online and offline behaviour). Some of this data is gathered from this website and others is gathered from advertisers. MediaGrid uses this data to provide its services. You may also utilize the Network Advertising Initiative’s opt-out page, the Digital Advertising Alliance’s opt-out page, or the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance’s opt-out page to opt-out of the use of cookies for interest-based advertising or review their privacy policy for more information.RevContent – You may find RevContent’s privacy policy through this link. RevContent may collect information about your browser or device, including browser type, IP Address, device type, user agent string, and operating system. RevContent also collects information about the websites you visit through their services, such as date and time of access and specific pages accessed and the content and ads you click on. You may opt-out of any personalization track by opting-out of RevContent’s data collection.Centro, Inc. – You may find Centro’s privacy policy through this link. You may find opt-out information for Centro’s services through the privacy policy link.33Across, Inc. – You may find 33Across’s privacy policy through this link. To opt-out of personalized advertising, please visit https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1.Conversant. LLC – You may find Conversant’s privacy policy through this link. Conversant uses information that does not directly identify you, such as information about your browser type, time and date of visit, your browsing or transaction activity, the subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over, and a unique identifier (such as a cookie string, or a unique advertising identifier provided by your mobile device) during your visits to this and other websites and apps in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. Conversant may use technologies such as cookies and other tracking technologies to collect this information. To learn more about interest-based advertising, or to opt-out, you can visit www.youronlinechoices.eu or https://www.networkadvertising.org/.And whilst you're here…Dave's Travel Pages is a travel blog that's been online since 2005. During that time, I've written literally thousands of travel guides and blog posts. Here's a starting point for you to jump right in…Greece Travel GuidesGreek Travel BlogsAthens Travel GuidesGreek Island Hopping GuideThailand Travel GuidesVietnam Travel GuidesMyanmar Travel GuidesNepal Travel GuidesTouring bike accessories and gearMy bike tours around the worldTouring bike reviewsCity Bike Hire SchemesBike Touring BlogsMeet the Cyclists Bike Touring interviews and blogs Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *CommentName * Email * Website
Recent Travel Posts
How to get from Mykonos to Andros by ferry in Greece
Mykonos to Tinos Ferry Information: Timetables, Tickets, Travel Tips
Mykonos to Ios Ferry Travel Explained: Routes, Connections, TicketsDave’s Travel Pages has a number of affiliate links placed within the travel blog. If you decide to buy items through these links, you will be helping Dave to fund this site and perhaps the next adventure. More importantly, it doesn’t cost you anything extra. Win win – we like that!Dave’s Travel Blog Privacy PolicyRead our privacy policy hereYou might also be interested in:Travel by BicycleTravel QuotesTravel to AthensGreek Island HoppingDave’s Santorini Travel GuideAs an Amazon Associate I earn from qualifying purchases.
